Guide to the collection Amos Gitai Film Archive M2266
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Amos Gitai film archive, circa 1980-2014
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Gitai, Amos, 1950-
Agav Films (Firm)
Sanselme, Marie-Jose
M2266
17 hard drive(s) (external) 1) Promised Land (Terre promise) 2002-2004; 2) Free Zone 2004-2005; 3) Disengagement 2005-2007; 4) One Day You Will Understand (Plus tard, tu comprendras) 2007-2008; 5) Home (documentary trilogy: House [1980] - A House in Jerusalem [1998] - News from home, News from House [2001]); 6) Tsili 2008-2014
7 Linear Feet Print material in 6 boxes, 2 half boxes, 1 flat box, 1 map folder
3 optical disc(s) (cd) 2 audio CDs + 1 data CD-R re: Klaus Barbie trial
9.5 gigabyte(s) 2,539 files from Marie-Jose Sanselme related to three films: House (trilogy), Plus Tard, and Tzili
Content Description
Materials consist of physical and digital files related to six of Amos Gitai's films, which have been organized into 6 series: Series 1. Promised Land, Series 2. Free Zone, Series 3. Disengagement, Series 4. One Day You'll Understand, Series 5. Home (triology), and Series 6. Tsili. Series 5 is further divided into the three films: House, House in Jerusalem, News from Home/News from House.
Conditions Governing Access
The physical portion of the collection is open for research. Note that material must be requested at least 36 hours in advance of intended use. The digital portion of the collection is CLOSED until processed.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift and purchase from Amos Gitai and Marie-Jose Sanselme; 2017. Accessions MSS 2017-265, 2017-288, 2017-298, and 2017-308.
Biographical / Historical
Amos Gitai (born 1950) is an Israeli filmmaker. His films, both documentaries as well as feature length films, are on topics of the Middle East and the Jewish-Arab conflict. Gitai has been invited to enter, among others, the Cannes Film Festival and the Venice Film Festival, and he has received several prestigious prizes for his work.
For more infirnatuin, please see http://www.amosgitai.com/html/home.asp
Amos Gitai Fond
Amos Gitai Fond: collection of films and documents by Amos Gitai at the Cinematheque, Paris, France (http://www.cineressources.net/repertoires/archives/fonds.php?id=gitai)
motion pictures (visual works); Motion picture producers and directors; Israel; Documentary films; Holocaust, Jewish (1939-1945); Human trafficking; Arab-Israeli conflict; Jerusalem -- History -- 20th century; Gitai, Amos, 1950-; Agav Films (Firm); Sanselme, Marie-Jose
- Series 1. Promised Land, 2002-2004
  - Synopsis of the film with original title of Fake, in English, French, and Hebrew (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Screenplay in English, French and in Hebrew (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Venezia 61 competition: invitation to participate and promotional catalog, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Promotional materials (poster, dvd cover) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Promotional poster Architektur museum, 2009 (Map-folder 10)
- Series 2. Free Zone, 2004-2005
  - Screenplay in French by Amos Gitai and Marie-Jose Sanselme, 2005-01-11 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Festival de Cannes 2005, Free Zone promotional catalog (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Press coverage and promotion, including in Cahiers du Cinema (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - A retrospective in Museo Nazionale del Cinema, Torino, Italy, 2006-09 (Map-folder 10)
- Series 3. Disengagement, 2005-2007
  - Screenplay in English by Amos Gitai and Marie-Jose Sanselme, 2005-11-24 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Screenplay in English, first draft "Gaza" by Amos Gitai and Marie-Jose Sanselme, 2006-08-28 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Screenplay in French by Amos Gitai and Marie-Jose Sanselme, 2006-08-01 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Screenplay in French by Amos Gitai and Marie-Jose Sanselme, 2007-02-01 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Screenplay in Hebrew (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Research files of filmed conversation in Hebrew (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Screenplay in Hebrew (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Screenplay in Hebrew and English, shooting in Israel (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Shooting script in Hebrew (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Toronto International Film Festival catalog, 2007-09-06-2007-09-15 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 64. Mostra internazionale d'arte cinematografica catalog (Half-box 3)
  - 31a Mostra Internacional de Cinema catalog, 2007-10-19-2007-11-01 (Half-box 3)
  - Osian's Cine: Festival of Asian and Arab Cinema catalog, 2008-07-10-2008-07-20 (Half-box 4)
  - 11th Yerevan International Film Festival catalog, 2014-07-13-2014-07-20 (Half-box 4)
  - Promotional materials (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Photocopy of photograph of Amos Gitai with Juliette Binoch (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - French press coverage (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Article in Hebrew; poster in Hebrew (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Poster in french advertising the film (Flat-box 6, Folder 1)
  - French and Italian press coverage (Flat-box 6, Folder 1)
  - Venezia 64 film festival promotional package (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Articles about the film and promotional materials from various film festivals (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Toronto International Film Festival press coverage (Flat-box 6, Folder 2)
  - Sao Paulo Film Festival press coverage (Flat-box 6, Folder 2)
- Series 4. One Day You'll Understand (Plus Tard, Tu Comprendras)
  - Synopsis in French, 2006-06-03 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Screenplay in French by Dan Franck and Jerome Clement, 2007-02-13 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Screenplay in French, 2006-08-05 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Screenplay in French by Dan Dranck and Jerome Clement, 2007-07-16 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Photographs of Amos Gitai and Jerome Clement (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Promotional postcard of film screening at Centre Pompidou (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Toronto International Film Festival catalog, 2008-09-04-2008-09-13 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Revue de presse, spiral bound book (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Fata Morgana, quadrimestrale di cinema e visioni, 2010-04 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Information relating to Klaus Barbie (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Notes, conversations and background information relating to the screenplay (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Press coverage in French (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Press coverage in Italian, Spanish and Portuguese (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Press coverage in English and German (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Press and promotional material (Flat-box 6, Folder 3)
  - Periodicals with articles about the film: Filmcritica, Tribune Juive, Telerama (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Photocopies of photographs
  - Photocopies of photographs, including Amos Gitai with Jeanne Moreau (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Series 5. Home (trilogy)
  - Subseries 1. House (first film of the documentary trilogy), 1980
    - Screenplay and post production screenplay in English (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Press coverage in English (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Press coverage in Hebrew and in German (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Press coverage (Flat-box 6, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 2. House in Jerusalem (second film of the documentary trilogy), 1980
    - Synopsis in French (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - DVD cover in French (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Katalog 34: Letni filmova skola (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 3. News from home, News from house (third film of the documentary trilogy), 2001
    - Synopsis in French (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Screenplay in French (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Photocopy of booklet for exposition at Architektur museum de TU Munich, 2009 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Film program of Museu d'Art Contemporani de Barcelona (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Press coverage in English (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Press coverage in French (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 4. Trilogy borders, 2005
    - La trilogie des frontieres, Jean Michel Frodon, in French (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Trilogy houses, Jean Michel Frodon, in Hebrew (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Series 6. Tsili, 2008-2014
  - Screenplay in French, 2011-11-07 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Screenplay in French with revisions, no date (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Screenplay in French, 2012-02-05 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Screenplay in French, 2012-02-18 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Screenplay in Hebrew (Box 9, Folder 3-5)
  - Shooting scene list (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - The book (The Story of a Life) by Aaron Appelfeld was adapted to the film Tsili (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Mostra Internazionale d'Arte Cinematografica la Biennale di Venezia 2014 - promotional material of the film (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Tsili, roman, by Aharon Appelfeld, 2 copies, one with annotations (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - 71. Mostra Internazionale d'Arte Cinematografica la Biennale di Venezia 2014 - catalog (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Press coverage in Italian - Film critica (Box 9, Folder 10)